RONNIE MUTULILI

P.O. Box 64723-00620, Nairobi, Kenya | Mobile: +254112411153 | Email: ronniemutulili@gmail.com Website: www.regulus-ventures.com

Professional Summary

An academically astute Aerospace Engineer with practical experience having worked in multi-disciplinary and multi-cultural environments locally and internationally in the United Kingdom. I have excellent problem-solving skills and proven ability to develop new concepts and techniques as showcased in my entrepreneur journey of my start-up company with a vision of replacing internal combustion motorbikes with electric motorbikes. I have in-depth knowledge of systems and design engineering along with project-based practical knowledge on product development process. I hold a BEng degree in Aerospace Engineering (awarded 2:1) from The University of the West of England where I also founded the East African Society providing a platform for young professionals to gain opportunities, employment and networking.

Core Skills

- Project management
- Research and development
- Operations management
- Teamwork
- Problem solving
- Leadership
- Innovation
- Excellent written and oral communication
- Customer relations

Relevant Professional Experience

Lead Engineer and Project Manager, Regulus Ventures, Nairobi, Sept 2020 - Dec 2021

- Led and managed a team of multi-disciplinary engineers in the research and development of an electric motorbike for the "boda-boda" sector in Kenya as an alternative to the current internal combustion motorbikes.
- Conducted and coordinated research and analysis related to electric mobility for the Siemens Stiftung's E-Mobility Innovation Call, qualifying up to the semi-finals for the competition.
- Developed strategies for research and data collection on sustainability of electric motorbikes in the Kenyan market.
 - Analysis of the data to determine consumer perception, insight and willingness to purchase.
- Responsible for developing and delivering progress and financial reports both internally and to the investors.
- Organized and attended meetings with Safipower, an established potential investor, who were
 interested in a symbiotic relationship where they would provide energy storage solution in form of
 solar powered battery to complement our electric motorbike.

Telecommunications Engineering Intern, Huawei Technologies, Nairobi, May 2016 – July 2016

- Part of a team tasked with installation and configuration of optical transmission platforms, cable management and directivity in Dense Wavelength Division Multiplexing (DWDM).
- Installed and maintained routers and switches in Nairobi using Internet Protocol Radio Access Network (IP RAN).

Project Manager, La Femme Engineering Services, Nairobi, July 2016 - Aug 2016

- Led and coordinated a team of 25 employees working on refurbishment of a in a high-risk area in conjunction with the lead contractor, Kenya Pipeline Company.
- Ensured all safety protocols and risk compliance was adhered to intermediary between the contractor and La Femme Engineering Services.

• Provided regular status updates, tracking and written reports of the project scope and progress for its entire duration.

IT Support Technician, La Femme Engineering Services, Nairobi, Jan 2015 - May 2016

- Part of a team in charge of maintenance, diagnosis, and repair of reported faults in equipment including printers and scanners. Helped in critical upgrade of company IT software and hardware.
- Initiated and implemented the deployment of the working practice to include IT in the field improved productivity of the company and saved time and over KSH 100,000 in annual costs.

Aeronautical Engineering, Attachment, BenAir Engineering, Moi Int. Airport, Mombasa Sept 2013 – Dec 2013

- Worked in a Part 145 Maintenance and Repair Organization (MRO) performing general aircraft maintenance in avionics on the L410 UVP-E9/20; Cessna Caravan C208B & DC3/C47-65 ARTP planes.
- Developed an aptitude for aircraft safety and workshop procedures while working on the aircrafts.

Aeronautical Engineering Attachment, Kenya Civil Aviation Authority (KCAA), Eldoret Airport June 2012 – Sep 2012

 Maintained KCAA facilities and equipment including Instrument Landing System, VHF Directional Finder, Distance Measuring Equipment, Doppler VHF Omni-Range Equipment, Information and Communication Technology, Radar, Aircraft Integrated Data System, VHF Radios, Very Small Aperture Terminal (VSAT).

Other Employment

Customer Service Assistant, Swissport International, Bristol Airport, June 2017 – Sep 2017

 Managing customer and client relations while meeting daily targets including checking passports, visas, and other relevant documentation for travel and adhering to all health, safety, and security regulations in the airport environment.

Personal Tutor, Tutorful, Bristol, Jan 2017 - April 2020

• Coordinating and training students in GCSE, A-Levels, IB and undergraduate levels in STEM subjects.

Education

Siemens Mechatronic System Certification Program (SMSPC), Dedan Kimathi University of Technology (DeKUT), Oct 2020 – Dec 2020

- Awarded grade: Mechatronic System Assistant
- Electrical Components, Mechanical Components and Electrical Drives, (Electro) Pneumatic and Hydraulic Control Circuits, Digital Fundamentals and Programmable Logic Controllers.
- Programming languages PLC, SCADA.

BEng (Hons) Aerospace Engineering, University of the West of England (UWE), Sept 2016 – Aug 2020

- Awarded grade: 2:1
- Extensive academic and practical background in: Design, Materials and Computer Aided Design (CAD), Aircraft systems, Avionics and Control, Mechatronics, Aero-structures, Aerodynamics, Stress and Dynamics, Project Management, and Thermodynamics.
- **Programming languages** Firm understanding in Python and C++. Used to program and automate an Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) in computer vision to automatically track a moving object using a Raspberry Pi camera.
- Final year dissertation: Detection of Component Degradation on Helicopter Epicyclic Secondary
 Planet Gears. The research focused on the Tunneling Magnetoresistance (TMR) technology to detect
 the change in magnetic flux density with simulated crack propagation in a secondary epicyclic planet
 gear. This would provide the maintenance crew real-time gear health monitoring and detection of

degradation in the main gearbox.

City and Guild Diploma in Aircraft Maintenance, Skypath Aviation College, Sept 2015 - June 2016

• Level 3 Diploma with distinction in Aircraft Maintenance (Civil Aircraft Electrical and Electronics).

Diploma Aeronautical Engineering, Avionics, East African School of Aviation, Sept 2010 - Nov 2014

- Diploma in Aeronautical Engineering in Avionics.
- Rugby Captain.
- Trade Project: Free Space Optical Communication using light propagation to wirelessly transmit data.

Professional Membership

- Engineering Board of Kenya (EBK), On course towards registering as a Graduate Engineer with EBK.
- Aero Society UWE, Member: designing and building drones, competing in the IMechE inter-university competitions, 2016.
- Institution of Engineering and Technology (IET), Student Member, 2016.
- Royal Aeronautical Society (RAeS), Student Affiliate, 2016.
- Institution of Mechanical Engineers (IMechE), Student member, 2016.

Certificates and Achievements

- Mechatronic System Assistant Siemens Mechatronic Systems Certification Program, SMSCP, 2020.
- East African Society UWE, Founder and President, 2017-2019.
- Winner: The Teamwork Award at the Student Experience Awards, Students Union, UWE, 2018.
- Certificate in Workplace Mentoring Faculty of Business and Law UWE, 2018.
- Elected: Lead Department Representative for the Department of Engineering, Design and Mathematics UWE, 2017.
- Certificate in APM Project Fundamentals Faculty of Environment and Technology, UWE, 2017.
- Certificate in AutoCAD Autodesk, 2016. No expiration date.
- Certificate in Health & Safety Huawei Technologies Ltd, 2016. No expiration date.

Nationality/Languages

- Kenyan
- English/Swahili

References

To be provided upon request.